# 首先我们准备新鲜玉米一条
First, take a fresh corncob
# 切成小段之后竖着用刀将玉米依次切下来
Chop it into short chunks, and then cut off the kernels
# 之前看过很多同学说蜂窝玉米用家庭小灶无法复制
Many comments said that it's impossible to follow the recipe of "Fengwo Yumi" ("honeycomb corn") with a less powerful stove at home
# 所以本期视频我来跟大家验证
So in this video, I'll verify for you
# 家庭小灶是否可行
whether it can be done with a home-style stove
# 玉米粒切下来之后放入碗中加入清水清洗干净
Wash the corn kernels in water
# 这一步的目的是去除玉米粒中夹杂的杂物
This is to remove the impurities
# 清洗干净之后倒出控干水分
After washing, take out and drain the corn kernels
# 下一步开始调糊
Next, prepare the coating
# 盆中加入鸡蛋两个
Add 2 eggs into the bowl
# 加入玉米淀粉200克
Add 200g of cornstarch
# 加入适量的玉米粉（约50克）
Add a moderate amount of cornmeal (~50g)
# 加入适量的土豆淀粉（约30克）
Add a moderate amount of potato starch (~30g)
# 最后加入适量的清水将主料调成糊
Finally, add water and mix the ingredients into slurry
# 清水必须少量多次加入调成糊状即可
Note that water must be added little by little, right until the ingredients can be mixed into slurry
# 主料调好之后下一步开始制作
After that, start cooking
# 首先我们在锅中加入宽油
First, add in "Kuan You" ("broad oil")
# 油的量需要按照蜂窝玉米的大小来定
The volume of the oil depends on the size of the "honeycomb corn"
# 所以必须匹配油的宽度否则成品不成形
So the oil must have a matching "broadness", otherwise the dish will end up in a bad shape
# 然后将油温烧至210度以上（七成热）
Then heat the oil to over 210°C (= 70% hot)
# 同学们油温必须高于210度
Note that the oil temperature must be over 210°C
# 否则主料下锅之后会沉淀变成一坨
Otherwise, the ingredients will sink to the bottom and end up in a bad shape
# 油温7成热之后将主料依次放入锅中
After reaching 70% hot, add the ingredients little by little
# 同学们注意这一步必须将玉米糊散开放入
Note that the corn slurry must be spread into the wok
# 主料下锅之后继续开中火炸两分钟
After putting in all the ingredients, deep fry over medium heat for 2min
# 将玉米糊炸至成型酥脆即可出锅装盘
After the corn becomes shaped and crispy, it's ready to serve
# 现在我们这个蜂窝玉米就做好了
Now our "Fengwo Yumi" ("honeycomb corn") is done
# 因为是在农村嘛方便四伯爷食用
As we are in the countryside, to make it easier for uncle
# 我把它敲碎
I'll crush it first
# 敲碎了好撒白糖
And then sprinkle some sugar on it
# 四伯爷你吃甜点吗
Uncle, would you like a sweeter taste?
# 甜点也行淡点也行
Sweeter is fine. Milder is also fine
# 我是随便啥子都可以的
Whatever is fine to me
# 我直接拿手哦
- I'll use my hands directly
Whatever is fine to me
# 要得啊
No problem
# 反正就拿手来弄
Just do it with my bare hands
# 应该四伯爷是第一次吃这个
Uncle, is it the first time you have this dish?
# 嗯
Yeah
# 第一次欣赏
My first time to appreciate it
# 这个很脆
This is quite crispy
# 如果不剁烂的话 我们在馆子里是
If we don't crush it... When in a restaurant
# 直接一整盘端上去
it will be served as a whole on a big plate
# 然后撒点糖在上面
and then we sprinkle sugar on it
# 吃 直接用手来吃
Try it. Use your hands
# 这个很脆吃起来
This is very crispy
# 嗯
Hmm
# 好吃
Delicious
# 是不很脆
Very crispy, isn't it?
# 很脆又很泡
Very crispy, and very puffy
# 嗯 很泡中间是泡的
Yeah, very puffy. It's filled with air
# 它中间是泡的所以
It's filled with air inside, so
# 叫 蜂窝玉米
it's called "Fengwo Yumi" ("honeycomb corn")
# 蜂窝不是有很多眼眼嘛
You know, a honeycomb has a lot of holes
# 它就跟这个差不多 炸出来一盘
Just like this. A whole plate of it
# 但是在家里的话有一个不好的地方就是
However, there's one thing bad at home that
# 火候掌握不了
it's too hard to get the right doneness
# 因为这个火太小了
because the power is too low.
# 我们炸这个的时候一定要中火来炸
We must use medium heat to cook this dish
# 如果在家里面做的话尽量就少放一点油
When cooking it at home, try to put less oil if possible
# 然后这个调下去慢慢放慢慢放
Then put in the slurry slowly, little by little
# 从边上开始放放到中间
Starting from the edge, and gradually proceed to the center
# 就是把它放得均匀一点千万不要堆成厚厚的一层
And it must be distributed evenly, instead of a thick pile
# 如果堆厚了的话
If you make it too thick
# 那就是一坨成不了蜂窝
then it ends up as a pile, not a honeycomb
# 是不是很有好脆
Very crispy, isn't it?
# 嗯
Hmm
# 这个东西还好吃
This thing tastes good
# 多吃点这个
Eat more
# 这个菜特别脆
This dish is really crispy
# 大家可以学一下
You may learn it at home
# 在家里面自己做
Try cooking it by yourself
# 这个小孩子是特别喜欢吃
Kids must love this dish
# 脆脆的
Crispy
# 有点香甜香甜的
And sweet
# 你咬得动撒
Can you chew it?
# 好啦 本期视频就到这里啦
All right, that's all for this video
# 拜拜
Bye bye